Grove Press Records
Grove Press Records
- Books - Book files (by author)
  - Young, Wayland
    - Eros Denied
      - Rights and permissions, 1967; 1971 (Box 743)
      - Royalties, Harold Matson (GP-311), 1964-1968 (Box 743)
      - Royalties, Harold Matson / Hudson Book Club (GP-311), 1964-1968 (Box 743)
      - Royalties, Harold Matson / Evergreen Book Club (GP-311), 1966-1969 (Box 743)
      - Royalties, Harold Matson (Z-1005), 1967-1970 (Box 743)
  - Yugoslavia Stories
    - Project file, 1959 (Box 743)
  - Zaturenska, Marya
    - Correspondence, Author, 1959-1960; 1965; includes letter from Seaver in his second week at Grove (Box 743)
    - Selected Poems of Marya Zaturenska
      - Contract, copyright, 1953; 1964 (Box 743)
      - Production, Manufacturing, 1955 (Box 743)
      - Publicity, 1954-1957 (Box 743)
      - Rights and permissions, 1959; 1963,; 1968 (Box 743)
      - Royalties, 1956-1961; some forms also include Terraces of Light (Box 743)
    - Terraces of Light
      - Contract, copyright, 1959-1960 (Box 743)
      - Correspondence, 1954; 1957-1965 (Box 743)
      - Production, Camera copy, 1960; Set A (Box 743)
      - Production, Camera copy, 1960; Set B, includes mechanicals for front matter (Box 743)
      - Production, Manufacturing, 1959-1960 (Box 743)
      - Production, Proofs (F&Gs / blues) (Box 743)
      - Royalties (E-202), 1955-1967 (Box 743)
  - Zeitlin, Maurice and Scheer, Robert
    - Cuba: Tragedy in Our Hemisphere
      - Correspondence, Author, 1963-1969; including letter from Zeitlin mentioning that co-author Scheer has acquired Che Guevera's diary from Fidel Castro. (Box 743)
      - Correspondence, 1963-1967; 1972 (Box 743)
      - Project file, 1963-1967; copyright certificate, typescript of preface with corrections/edits, corrected draft of table of contents, few pages of galley, clipping of letter to the editor (Box 744)
      - Publicity, Grove, includes Zeitlin's publicity questionnaire (Box 744)
      - Publicity, General, 1963-1969; includes articles by Zeitlin, review from Fair Play for Cuba Committee (Lee Harvey Oswald's "communist affiliation") only months before JFK assassination and clipping from National Guardian with book review on one side and article about Oswald's assassination on the other (Box 744)
      - Royalties (BD-55), 1963-1969 (Box 744)
  - Zepol, See Justine, or, The Misfortunes of Virtue - comic book version.
  - Zichy, Mihaly
    - The Erotic Drawings of Mihaly Zichy
      - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 744)
      - Illustrations, 1968; transparencies for pen and ink illustrations and contact sheets (Box 744)
      - Production, Manufacturing, 1970 (Box 744)
      - Production, setting copy, 1969; front matter only (Box 744)
      - Royalties, Gala Verlag (GP-555), 1966-1970 (Box 744)
  - Zilboorg, Gregory
    - Sigmund Freud: His Exploration of the Mind of Man
      - Contract, 1960 (Box 744)
      - Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 744)
      - Production, Manufacturing, 1960 (Box 744)
      - Royalties, Scribner's Sons (E-239), 1960-1963 (Box 744)
  - Ziporyn, Marvin, See Altman, Jack and Marvin Ziporyn: Born to Raise Hell.
  - Zola, Emile
    - Earth
      - Contract, 1954 (Box 744)
      - Production, Manufacturing, 1954-1960 (Box 744)
      - Project file, 1954-1959 (Box 744)
      - Publicity, 1954-1956 (Box 744)
      - Publicity, 1955 (Box 744)
      - Royalties, Elek Books (HB-68), 1955-1961 (Box 744)
  - Zong, In-Sob
    - Folk Tales From Korea
      - Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 744)
      - Production, Manufacturing, 1979 (Box 744)
      - Publicity, 1952-1954; majority is clippings, includes a few letters (Box 744)
  - Zwang, Gerald
    - Le Sexe de la Femme
      - Contract, 1967 (Box 745)
      - Correspondence, Harold Salemson (translator), 1968-1969 (Box 745)
      - Project file, 1967-1969; check requests, clipping, a few letters to/from Pauvert (Box 745)
      - Royalties, Georges Borchardt, 1967-1971 (Box 745)
  - Zwerenz, Gerhard
    - Little Peter in War and Peace, alternate title: Casanova; original German title: Der Kleine Herr in Krieg und Frieden
      - Contract, 1967 (Box 745)
      - Correspondence, Author, 1970; 1976 (Box 745)
      - Correspondence, Bill Whitman (translator), 1967-1969 (Box 745)
      - Correspondence, general, 1966-1973 (Box 745)
      - Production, Galleys, 1970; 2 folders (Box 745)
      - Production, Manufacturing, 1970 (Box 745)
      - Production, setting copy, 1970; 5 folders (Box 745)
      - Project file, 1966-1973; sample translation, serval pages of typescript with correction, queries about various German words, internal notes and memos, etc. (Box 745)
      - Publicity, 1970 (Box 745)
      - Royalties, Maximilian Becker, 1967-1970 (Box 745)
  - Unidentified or multiple authors
    - Correspondence, 1963; 1966-1973,; undated; includes notes or reports from Rossett, Seaver and others on the status of numerous Grove titles (Box 1127)
    - Manuscripts
      - [Czech interviews], photocopy of typescript in Czech, containing inteviews with Dominik Tatarka, Peter Karaus, Lumir Ciurny (Box 1127)
      - One's Life the Eternal Moment, typescript carbon (Box 1127)
      - Resistance book, 1969-1970; numerous clippings, partial book outline; topics include student dissent, draft avoidance, conscientious objectors, etc. (Box 1127)
      - Star tattoo dying on the day-glo Ganges, galleys of a poem (Box 1127)
      - Susan's Cookbook, typescript (Box 1127)
      - Unidentified fragments, pieces from two or three different typescripts, some with corrections (Box 1127)
      - Index to unidentified book, card file (Box 1000)
      - Index to unidentified book, 2 card files (Box 1001)
    - Photographs, black and white, unidentified; some with layout instructions; includes one page of sleeved negatives (Box 746)
    - Poster, unidentfiied, large white poster with black and white pictures, possibly movie stills (Map-case 108)
    - Production, Miscellaneous (Box 746)
    - Rights and permissions
      - Agents and publishers, 1961-1973; correspondence and requests from various agents and publishers, in alphabetical order by name; 2 folders (Box 746)
      - Book Fair, 1970; relating to Frankfurt Book Fair (Box 746)
      - Copyright, miscellaneous, 1985; undated; includes a few specific titles (mostly biographies) which did not appear in the "Book files" section, Library of Congress certificates, notes, etc.; 2 folders (Box 746)
      - Others, 1961-1970; requests from individuals, in chronological order (Box 746)
      - Others, 1971-1973; 1983; requests from individuals, in chronological order (Box 1106)
    - Royalties, Modern Americn Usage; Collect Nat West (Box 1106)
    - Subsidiary income, includes two folders mostly Eric Berne, one folder of material relating to Castle Books; 6 folders (Box 1106)
    - Subsidiary income, 3 folders (Box 1107)
- Books - Correspondence-subject files
  - Academy of American Poets, 1965 (Box 747)
  - Adams, Lionie, 1952 (Box 747)
  - Ad Club meeting, 1962 (Box 747)
  - Adelmann, Marianne (photographer), 1966 (Box 747)
  - Agents
    - Agence Hoffman, 1966-1970; 1972,; 1974,; 1976; Dagmer Henne, others (Box 747)
    - Am-Rus Literary and Music Agency, 1956-1960; 1964 (Box 747)
    - American Literary Exchange, 1954-1959 (Box 747)
    - Arnaud, Odette, 1952-1953; 1958-1959 (Box 747)
    - Authors Publishers International Agency (APIA), 1952-1956 (Box 747)
    - A, miscellaneous (Box 747)
    - Balkin Agency, 1973-1977; includes photocopy of Chomsky letter (Box 747)
    - Bar-David Literary Agency, 1960 (Box 747)
    - Barthold Fles, 1956-1957 (Box 747)
    - Bauer, William, 1953 (Box 747)
    - Blassingame, Lurton, 1952-1957 (Box 747)
    - Borchardt, Georges, 1958-1977; 1981; 5 folders (Box 747)
    - Borchardt, Georges, 1953-1973; Michelle Lapautre (Box 747)
      See also Lapautre, Michelle below.
    - Boyd, Madeline, 1952 (Box 748)
    - Bradley, W. A., 1952 (Box 748)
    - Brandt and Brandt, 1952-1960; 1965-1966,; 1974 (Box 748)
    - B, miscellaneous (Box 748)
    - Christie, Margaret, 1952-1953; 1959 (Box 748)
    - Clairouin, 1954-1960 (Box 748)
    - Colin, Rosica, 1952-1955; 1958-1963,; 1967-1970,; 1976; 3 folders (Box 748)
    - Collier Associates, 1976-1977 (Box 748)
    - Corti, Jose, 1953; 1957 (Box 748)
    - Curtis-Brown, Anne, 1965 (Box 748)
    - Curtis Brown Ltd., 1953-1956; 1959,; 1962,; 1966,; 1971 (Box 748)
    - C, miscellaneous (Box 748)
    - Daves, Joan, 1973-1976 (Box 748)
      See also Marie Rodell and Joan Daves Ltd., below.
    - Dilia, 1971; undated (Box 748)
    - D, miscellaneous (Box 748)
    - Edward Sommerfield Ltd., 1961 (Box 748)
    - Elliott, Desmond, 1959 (Box 748)
    - Elmo, Ann, 1959; 1965 (Box 748)
    - Estelle Mandel Agents for Creative Artists, 1970 (Box 748)
    - Franz J. Horch Associates, 1953-1954; 1956-1960,; 1966,; 1969 (Box 748)
    - F, miscellaneous (Box 748)
    - Geisenheyner & Crone, 1963-1964 (Box 748)
    - Gregory, Fitch and Hendricks, 1953; 1955 (Box 748)
    - G, miscellaneous (Box 748)
    - Hanna-Kristi Koch, 1953 (Box 748)
    - Harold Matson, 1954; 1968-1971,; 1973-1974 (Box 748)
    - Harold Ober Associates, 1952-1959; 1962,; 1966,; 1970,; 1981 (Box 748)
    - Helga Greene Literary Agency, 1953 (Box 748)
    - Hellmer, Kurt, 1953-1958; 1961 (Box 748)
    - Herman, R.J., 1952 (Box 748)
    - Hope Leresche and Steele / Hope Leresche and Sayle, 1963; 1971-1977 (Box 748)
    - H, miscellaneous (Box 748)
    - Ingersoll and Brennan, 1957-1958 (Box 748)
    - Ingo Preminger Agency, 1955 (Box 748)
    - International Famous Agency, 1970-1971 (Box 748)
    - International Literary Agency, 1965; 1970-1971 (Box 748)
      See also Klausner, Bertha.
    - I, miscellaneous (Box 748)
    - Jackinson, Alex, 1958; 1965 (Box 748)
    - Jacques Chambrun Inc., 1955; 1959 (Box 748)
    - Jay Garon-Brooke Associates, 1953 (Box 748)
    - John Farquharson, 1952 (Box 748)
    - John Grant, 1961 (Box 748)
    - Joseph, Nannine, 1952-1953 (Box 748)
    - Julian Bach, 1969-1971; 1974-1975 (Box 748)
    - J, miscellaneous (Box 748)
    - King, Eleanor, 1955; 1959 (Box 749)
    - Klausner, Bertha, 1952-1953; 1956-1959,; 1965 (Box 749)
      See also International Literary Agency.
    - K, miscellaneous (Box 749)
    - Lapautre, Michele, 1968-1969 (Box 748)
      See also Borchardt, Georges.
    - Laurence Pollinger Limited, 1958 (Box 748)
    - Lennart Sane Agency, 1969-1970 (Box 748)
    - Louis Navarra and Associates, 1953 (Box 748)
    - L, miscellaneous (Box 749)
    - Margaret Ramsey Ltd., 1959; 1963,; 1977 (Box 749)
    - Marie Rodell and Joan Daves Ltd., 1952-1957; 1959,; 1961-1962 (Box 749)
      See also Daves, Joan above.
    - Marion Saunders, 1952-1953 (Box 749)
    - MCA Management, 1952-1953; 1958 (Box 749)
    - McCrindle, J.F., 1954; 1956,; 1959 (Box 749)
    - McIntosh and McKee, 1952; 1955,; 1958-1959 (Box 749)
    - Meyer, Helmut, 1953-1955 (Box 749)
    - Monica McCall, 1955 (Box 749)
    - Moorepark, Howard, 1952-1953; 1955-1959,; 1966-1967,; 1972-1973 (Box 749)
    - Murray, Natalie, 1952-1953; 1959 (Box 749)
    - M, miscellaneous (Box 749)
    - Nat Sobel Associates, 1974-1977; 1981 (Box 749)
    - Noth, Elena, 1953-1955 (Box 749)
    - N-O, miscellaneous (Box 749)
    - Paul Reynolds and Son, 1952-1953; 1956,; 1960,; 1967 (Box 749)
    - Pearn, Pollinger and Higham, 1953; 1956 (Box 749)
    - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1966-1971 (Box 749)
    - P, miscellaneous (Box 749)
    - Ronald Hobbs (Box 749)
    - Roslyn Targ, 1965-1973; "Scandinavia, Spanish, Portugal, Japan" (Box 749)
    - Rothenborg, Jorgen, 1968-1971 (Box 749)
      See Books: Book files: Rothenborg, Jorgen.
    - Rottensteiner, Franz, 1975-1977 (Box 750)
    - Russell and Volkening, 1952-1953; 1955 (Box 750)
    - R, miscellaneous (Box 750)
    - Samuel French, 1971; mostly regarding Beckett (Box 750)
    - Sanford J. Greenburger, 1953; 1959,; 1966 (Box 750)
    - Schaffner, John, 1952-1960 (Box 750)
    - Scott Meredith, 1959; 1973 (Box 750)
    - Seligmann and Collier, 1969; 1971,; 1974-1976 (Box 750)
    - Shirley Hector Agency, 1954; 1956-1957,; 1959 (Box 750)
    - Spodheim, Renee, 1955-1960; 1963,; 1970 (Box 750)
    - Staletti, Luca, 1968 (Box 750)
    - Sterling Lord, 1956-1959; 1965,; 1969,; 1974,; 1976 (Box 750)
    - S, miscellaneous (Box 750)
    - Toby Cole, 1972-1973 (Box 750)
    - T, miscellaneous (Box 750)
    - William Morris Agency, 1952-1954; 1959,; 1962,; 1966-1967,; 1970,; 1976-1977,; 1981 (Box 750)
    - Wolf, Harriet, 1952-1953 (Box 750)
    - Woodburn, Eve, 1952 (Box 750)
    - Wright, Ellen, 1953-1956; 1968 (Box 750)
    - Writer's Service, 1956; 1959 (Box 750)
    - W, Y, Z, miscellaneous (Box 750)
  - Alison, Barley, 1967-1970 (Box 750)
  - Allen, Don, 1953-1965; 12 folders (Box 750)
  - Allen, Don, 1966-1974; 6 folders (Box 751)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1955-1956 (Box 751)
  - American Book Publishers Council, 1957; 1960; annual sales trend survey (Box 751)
  - American Book Publishers Council, 1957-1958; 1963; Censorship Bulletin, Freedom to Read Bulletin (Box 751)
  - American Book Publishers Council, 1956-1970; correspondence (Box 751)
  - American Book Publishers Council, 1956-1957; salary survey (Box 751)
  - American Literary Anthology, George Plimpton, 1969 (Box 751)
  - American Psychological Association, 1959 (Box 751)
  - American Society of Magazine Photographers, 1959; directory (Box 751)
  - Angry Arts, 1967 (Box 751)
  - Antiquariaat W.N. Schors, 1970 (Box 751)
  - Aronowitz, Al, 1970 (Box 751)
  - Art Directors Club, 1957; 1958,; 1969; awards and certificates given to Grove Press (Oversize 33)
  - Art history book series, 1961; Editions du Seuil; 2 folders (Box 751)
  - Artists Civil Rights Assistance Fund, 1964 (Box 751)
  - Ashbery, John, 1968 (Box 751)
  - Asia/Africa series, 1960-1963; Weidenfeld and Nicholson (Box 751)
  - Asia Society, 1958; 1961,; 1968 (Box 751)
  - Aubry, Marcel, 1948 (Box 751)
  - Author address requests (alphabetical by author), 3 folders (Box 752)
  - A, miscellaneous (Box 752)
  - Balakian, Nona (New York Times Book Review), 1958-1959 (Box 752)
  - Barry, Joseph (New York Post), 1961-1962 (Box 752)
  - Bauer, Jerry (photographer), 1961-1973; 2 folders (Box 752)
  - Berenstein-Cohen, D., 1953; concerning Israel (Box 752)
  - Bergman, Peter (Polyglot Press), 1960-1961 (Box 752)
  - Bess, Donovan, 1960 (Box 752)
  - Bettmann Archive, 1959 (Box 752)
  - Bibliotheque Internationale D'Erotologie series, 1965; 1971 (Box 752)
  - Big Table Books (Follett Publishing), 1969-1970 (Box 752)
  - Birns and Sawyer, 1975-1976 (Box 752)
  - Bishop, Helen Gary, 1975; to, from, and about (Box 752)
  - Black Cat books, 1962; 1967 (Box 752)
  - Book clubs
    - Biography Book Club, 1952; clippings (Box 752)
    - Book Find Club (Braziller), 1952-1960; 1964,; 1967 (Box 752)
    - Book of the Month Club, 1952-1955; 1959 (Box 752)
    - Dolphin Book Club, 1957-1958; 1960 (Box 752)
    - East and West Book Club, 1956-1958; includes Book News, reviews, clippings; 3 folders (Box 753)
    - Hudson Book Club, 1966; undated; correspondence, bulletins (Box 753)
    - Mid-Century Book Society, 1959-1960; 1965-1967; brochures, clippings, correspondence, sales selections and reports; 4 folders (Box 753)
    - Paperback Book Club, 1965 (Box 753)
    - Psychiatry and Social Science Book Center, 1967; 1970 (Box 753)
    - Reader's Subscription, 1952-1959; 1966 (Box 753)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1953-1958; 1961-1963,; 1967 (Box 753)
  - Book Press, 1965; 1968; includes list of books lost in fire (Box 753)
  - Book racks, 1958-1960; Eberhard Rensch, John Calder; 2 folders (Box 753)
  - Bookseller's League, 1959; photos of Ungerer, Rosset, O'Hara, Rembar, Koch (Box 753)
  - Braverman, Harry, 1962-1970; 1973; includes correspondence with Barney Rosset and Dick Seaver, New York Times letter to the editor from HB about Invitation to an Inquest (Box 753)
  - Breit, Harvey, 1953-1956; includes photo of Breit (Box 753)
  - Brentano's Bookstore, 1963; 1965-1968,; 1970 (Box 753)
  - British Income Tax, 1963-1964; 1969-1970; 2 folders (Box 753)
  - Brown, James Oliver (James Brown Associates), 1962-1966 (Box 753)
  - de Brunhoff, Laurent and Marie-Claude, 1967-1968 (Box 753)
  - Bugental, James, 1966; includes outline of book (Box 753)
  - Bulletin du Livre, 1963-1969 (Box 753)
  - B, miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 754)
  - Cadoo, Emil (photographer), 1962-1970; undated; 2 folders (Box 754)
  - Caetani, Princess Marguerite, 1953-1955 (Box 754)
  - Cage, John (about), 1959 (Box 754)
  - Cahiers du Cinema, 1968-1971; includes contract; reader's reports; rights and permissions; 3 folders (Box 754)
  - Campbell, Joseph, 1959 (Box 754)
  - Canadian copyright, 1961-1962 (Box 754)
  - Cantone, Vic (Box 754)
  - Carroll, Kent, 1981 (Box 754)
  - Carruth, Hayden, 1955 (Box 754)
  - Censorship (magazine), 1967 (Box 754)
  - Censorship, problems with (other than Grove), 1964-1965 (Box 754)
  - Center for Inter-American Relations, 1969 (Box 754)
  - Children's books
    - Burke Books, 1967-1969 (Box 754)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1968; bulk is internal, from Louise Stallard; 2 folders (Box 754)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1970; bulk is internal, from Louise Stallard (Box 755)
    - Illustrators, 1967-1969 (Box 755)
    - Manuscript inquiries and submissions, 1967-1969 (Box 755)
    - Nielson, John and Kay, 1967; 1969 (Box 755)
    - Oliver and Boyd, 1967-1968 (Box 755)
    - Publicity, catalogs, brochures, proofs of artwork, etc. (Box 755)
    - Rejections, 1966-1969; 4 folders (Box 755)
  - Choudhury, Malay Roy, 1966-1970 (Box 756)
  - Cluchey, Douglas, 1966 (Box 756)
  - Cohen, Maxwell T., 1960 (Box 756)
  - Cole, Nancy, 1965; includes copy of chapbook, "Hommage a Gertrude Stein" (Box 756)
  - College Department, 1967-1969; 1977 (Box 756)
  - College adoptions, card file, ordered by book number (Box 1000)
  - College and school adoptions, 1960s; 3 folders (Box 756)
  - Colorado Booksellers Association, 1963 (Box 756)
  - Columbia Pictures, 1953; 1968-1969 (Box 756)
  - Columbia Writer's Conference, 1963-1965 (Box 756)
  - Combs, George Hamilton (WBAI), 1958 (Box 756)
  - Complaints (Box 756)
  - Compliments and thanks (Box 756)
  - Complimentary copies, 1970; for Grove employees and others (Box 756)
  - Congress of Racial Equality, 1962 (Box 756)
  - Contracts (blank) (Box 756)
  - Contributions
    - Book donations, 1957-1967; 11 folders (Box 1100)
    - Book donations, 1968-1973; undated; 5 folders (Box 1101)
    - Financial, 1953-1959; 1965-1972; 2 folders (Box 1101)
  - Cooper, D.B., 1971-1972; letter allegedly from Cooper, proposing book (Box 757)
  - Copyright, 1952-1969; 2 folders (Box 757)
    See also Library of Congress.
  - Cousins, Norman, 1967 (Box 757)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, 1952-1953; 1964 (Box 757)
  - Crank and derogatory letters (Box 757)
  - Crumb, R., 1969 (Box 757)
  - Cuba trip, 1970 (Box 757)
  - Customer complaints, postcard responses, 1969 (Box 757)
    See also Complaints above, for longer letters.
  - C, miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 757)
  - Darien House, 1965 (Box 757)
  - Davis, Arthur, 1962 (Box 757)
  - Deardoff, Ken, 1974-1976 (Box 757)
  - Dell distribution, 1961; 1972-1973; 3 folders (Box 757)
  - Dell publishing meeting minutes, 1961 (Box 757)
  - Denby, Edwin, 1957-1958 (Box 758)
  - Deutscher, Isaac, 1959; 1963-1965 (Box 758)
  - La Diffusion Francaise, 1958-1959 (Box 758)
  - Dine, Jim, clippings, typescript of interview possibly by Dick Seaver, photographs of Dine's paintings, disbound Pauvert edition of Les larmes d'Eros par Georges Bataille (Box 1119)
  - Dino de Laurentiis Cinematografia, 1965 (Box 758)
  - Distribution, Australia, 1980 (Box 758)
  - Documenta (Box 758)
  - Dommergue, Pierre, 1965; 1967 (Box 758)
  - Dorfman, Elsa ("Ellie"), 1967-1970 (Box 758)
  - Dowden, George, 1968 (Box 758)
  - Dun and Bradstreet, 1962 (Box 758)
  - Dylan, Bob, photocopy of "Tarantula" (Box 758)
  - D, miscellaneous (Box 758)
  - Edel, Leon, 1959 (Box 758)
  - Editorial ideas, 1953-1955 (Box 758)
  - Editorial meetings, 1970 (Box 758)
  - Electro plate sales, 1959-1960 (Box 758)
  - Environment (magazine), 1969-1970; Sheldon Novick, regarding collection of articles/essays (Box 758)
  - Esquire, 1959; 1969 (Box 758)
  - Eros, 1964 (Box 758)
  - Europe file, 1968-1969; contact information, miscellaneous telegrams, foreign rights information (Box 758)
  - Evergreen Award for New Campus Writing, 1960-1961 (Box 758)
  - Evergreen Books Ltd, 1962; 1966,; 1971-1972 (Box 758)
  - Evergreen Encyclopedias, 1958-1959; publicity (Box 758)
  - Exportfilm, 1976 (Box 758)
  - Exposition Editorial del Continente Americano, 1964; Mexico award (Box 758)
  - E, miscellaneous (Box 758)
  - Fadiman, Clifton, 1956 (Box 758)
  - Farrell, James T., 1953-1959; 1966 (Box 758)
  - Feffer and Simons, 1964; 1966,; 1968,; 1975 (Box 758)
  - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, 1960; 1962; includes letter regarding Cuba (Box 758)
  - Field, Edward, 1975-1976 (Box 758)
  - Fitzsimmons, Tom, 1954; 1958-1959,; 1964,; 1969 (Box 758)
  - Flicker, Theodore (Greatriver Productions/Crystal Palace), 1958 (Box 758)
  - Foreign translation rights, lists of (Box 758)
  - Forms, form letters, internal forms, etc. (Box 759)
  - Forum, the University of Houston Quarterly Conference, 1959 (Box 759)
  - Frankfurt Book Fair, 1965-1970; 11 folders (Box 759)
  - Frankfurt Book Fair, 1983; 1985; 2 folders (Box 760)
  - Freund, Philip, 1957 (Box 760)
  - Friar, Kimon, 1952-1954; 1969,; 1973; includes biographcal sketch, letter from customer complaining about Grove's sponsorship (Box 760)
  - Friedmann, Tomas/PIP Photos, 1966; 1970 (Box 760)
  - F, miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 760)
  - Gablik, Suzi, 1956-1957 (Box 760)
  - Gallen, Richard ("Dick"), 1966; 1969,; 1974-1975,; 1979; legal matters (Box 760)
  - Gallery Books contract, 1958; Cahiers de musee de poche/Georges Fall (Box 760)
  - Gallery Books correspondence, 1952; 1958-1965,; 1970; 2 folders (Box 760)
  - Gallery Books photo list, Georges Fall (Box 760)
  - Gallery Books possibilities, 1959-1961; possible books, reference to Motherwell (Box 760)
  - Gallery Books publicity, 1959-1960 (Box 760)
  - Gallery magazine, 1959-1960 (Box 760)
  - Geismar, Maxwell, 1954; 1956-1957,; 1962,; 1965 (Box 760)
  - General book inquiries (by author of book)
    - Anonymous (Box 760)
      Fille de Joie, My Secret Life, The Pearl
    - A (Box 760)
      Abt, Allen, Anderson, Apollinaire, Arrabal
    - B (Box 760)
      Barea, Barrett, Beckett, Behan, Behn, Berne, Bertrand, Biely, Biermann, Blackburn, Blesh, nBrecht, Brenan, Briggs, Browning, Burroughs
    - C (Box 761)
      Caldwell, Carim, Cesaire, Chekhov, Clark, Cocteau, Coe, Collins, Crashaw, Cremer, Crommelynck, Crouzet, Cummings
    - D-G (Box 761)
      Danziger, Del Boca, Dreifus, Dumont, Duras, Durrell, Durrenmatt, Ebin, Egerton, Fanon, Field, Firbank, Forest, Frank, Fraigneau, Gagliano, Genet, Ginsberg, Girodias, Githens, Goldberg, Gombrowicz, Gorky, Gover, Guieu
    - H-L (Box 761)
      H.D., Halasz, Harris, Harris, Haskins, Hobson, Hochhuth, Hodeir, Hoffman, Holt, Huang Po, Hughes, Hutchinson, Ionesco, Jameson, Jean, Jones (E.), Jones (T.), Kagan, Kaiser, Kerouac, Klein, Koch, Kronhausen, Kupferberg, Lam, Lang, Larner, Lawrence, Lebel, Legman, Lewes, Liehm, Lillo, Lind, Lipton, Loovis
    - M-O (Box 761)
      Martin, Matthys, Maurois, Miller, Mills, Mishima, Mitchel, Morin, Moss, Nefzaoui, Neruda, Ney, Nichols, Nims, Noonan, Norman, O'Connor, Oe, O'Hara, Ollier, Olson, Owens
    - P-S (Box 761)
      Panduro, Philby, Pieyre de Mandiargue, Pinget, Pinter, Popkin, Porter, Rahula, Reage, Rechy, Reynolds, Robbe-Grillet, Robinson, Rosenthal, Rosewicz, Rosset, Roy, Rulfo, Russian Revolutionary Posters, Sade, Sager, Schneebaum, Schutz, Semprun, Shaw, Sims, Snow, Steiner, Stoppard, Suzuki
    - T-X (Box 761)